Guide to the Robert O. Tilman Papers
Robert O. Tilman Papers
- Reference Files
  - Publications
    - Publications - Miscellaneous and Undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Personal Files
  This series contains miscellaneous non-professional material relating to Tilman and his wife Jo. Correspondence relating to the estate of Mrs. Tilman’s mother, greeting cards, and various other documents are included.
  - Blue Cross (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Cards - Dickens Disciples, Raleigh NC (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Appreciation (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Clock (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Estate (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Greeting Cards (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Documents (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Paper by Jo Tilman (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Calendars (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Business Cards (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Audio-Visual Material
  This series contains various video cassettes, audio reels, slides, and photographs relating both to Tilman’s professional career and personal life. Slides include images of various Southeast Asian countries. Many of the audio reels contain music, and several are unidentified.
  - Photographs
    - Photographs (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Wedding Album (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Videos
    - China: Part I & II (Carton 31)
    - Coming of Age, 1987; 1987 1987 (Carton 31)
    - Great Decisions '87 (tape 1 of 2) (Carton 31)
    - Great Decisions '87 (part 2 of 2) (Carton 31)
    - On a Ledge (Carton 31)
    - Messages and Methods: Telecommunication (Carton 31)
    - Singapore (Carton 31)
    - There Is No God (Carton 31)
    - "Who are the Japanese?", "The NC-Japan Connection", "My Name is Moto" (Carton 31)
    - VHS Dub of Japan Doc (Carton 31)
    - Violence and Capital Punishment (Carton 31)
  - Slides
    - AOT's and Pop, Jill, Baby, Sissy, Misc., USA (Carton 34)
    - Far East: Hong Kong, Japan, Korea, Taiwan (Carton 36)
    - Friends, Pets, Jane's Wedding (Carton 35)
    - HK, London, Athens, Canada (Carton 34)
    - Malaysia I, 1959-1970; 1959 1970 (Carton 34)
    - Malaysia II (Carton 35)
    - Mexico, 1972; 1972 1972 (Carton 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Carton 34)
    - Miscellaneous (Carton 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Carton 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Carton 36)
    - Philippines (Class), 1969-1970; 1969 1970 (Carton 35)
    - Philippines I, 1969-1970; 1969 1970 (Carton 35)
    - Philippines II (Carton 35)
    - Philippines III (Carton 35)
    - Rejects (Carton 36)
    - Singapore (Carton 35)
    - Xmas '74 Barbados, Xmas '75 Hawaii (Carton 34)
    - Xmas '73 Cruise, Xmas '76 Arizona (Carton 34)
  - Audio
    - A Talk With Ho Chi Minh (Carton 31)
    - Al Jolson; The Pearl Trio (Carton 31)
    - Alley Cat; Herb Alpert (Carton 31)
    - Andy Williams: Moon River and Other Great Movie Themes (Carton 31)
    - Answering Machine Cassette (Carton 31)
    - Asean (Carton 31)
    - Background Music (Carton 31)
    - Bands and Pipes of the Grenadier Guards (Carton 31)
    - The Best of Peter Sellers (Carton 31)
    - Christmas Music (Carton 31)
    - Dr. Robert Tilman (Carton 31)
    - Excerpts from Earl Long's Speeches (Carton 31)
    - Glen Miller (Carton 31)
    - Lesson II, Lesson III (Carton 31)
    - Lesson III, Part II (Carton 31)
    - Lesson III, Part 2 (Carton 31)
    - Lesson 6 (Carton 31)
    - "Malaysia and the Balance of Power in Southeast Asia" (Carton 31)
    - Ormandy Philadelphia Orchestra (Carton 31)
    - Orson Welles - "War of the Worlds"; "The Years to Remember" (Carton 31)
    - Philharmonia Orchestra - Dvorak Symphony; Bergen International Festival (Carton 31)
    - Retreat '75 Tape 1 (Carton 31)
    - Retreat '75 Tape 2 (Carton 31)
    - Sigmund Romberg's The Student Prince (Carton 31)
    - Vivaldi; Mozart; Schutz (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
    - Unidentified (Carton 31)
  - Diskettes (Carton 37)
    - VIII TIG MS DOS (Carton 37)
    - TIGBIB (Carton 37)
    - TIGINDEX IBM (Carton 37)
    - II ASEAN IBM (New Copy) (Carton 37)
    - I TIGER (Carton 37)
    - III POLFO MSDOS (Carton 37)
    - IV Part MSDOS (Carton 37)
    - V CHINA (Carton 37)
    - GLOSSARY TIGLOSS (Carton 37)
    - VI JAPAN (Carton 37)
    - VII USA (Carton 37)
    - 231 (Carton 37)
    - ADDBOOK PC (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory - WS 1 of 3 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory - WS 2 of 3 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory - WS 3 of 3 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory - WS 3 of 3 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory -SP8TROLL 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Microstu 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Microtes 1 of 2 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Microtes 2 of 2 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Modem 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Perfect 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Search 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Tutor 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Dr. TIlman's Files Subdirectory Tutor 1 of 1 (Carton 37)
    - Wordstar, Wordplus (Carton 37)
    - Unlabeled (Carton 37)
    - Uniform S-Basic (Carton 37)
    - Wordstar, Wordplus, Footnote, Stat (Carton 37)
    - MITE (Office Copy) (Carton 37)
    - TX104085 (1986) (Carton 37)
    - Perfect Calc for Singapore (Carton 37)
    - 1984 Income Tax (Carton 37)
    - Grant Accounting (PC) (Carton 37)
    - Working Diskette Perfect Calc (Carton 37)
    - TX104084 (1985) (Carton 37)
    - Working Diskette Microsoft Basic-80 (Carton 37)
    - Notebook Program (Carton 37)
    - Working Diskette Microplan, C-Basic (Carton 37)
    - Instillation Disk Perfect Writer (Carton 37)
    - Footnote (Carton 37)
    - Working Diskette CP/M Version 2.2, S-Basic (Carton 37)
    - Edit Disk Perfect Writer (Carton 37)
    - Lessons Disk Perfect Writer (Carton 37)
    - Income Tax Program Copy Files (Carton 37)
    - Notebook Database (Carton 37)
    - Notebook Backup (Carton 37)
    - Filer Disk Perfect Filer (Carton 37)
    - Footnote Kaypro SN RA 178 Master (Carton 37)
    - Footnote Kaypro SN RA 178 Master (Carton 37)
    - Bibliography Kaypro SN RA 178 Master (Carton 37)
    - Grammatik Kaypro SN RA 178 Master (Carton 37)
    - Random House Proofreader Kaypro SN RA 178 Master (Carton 37)
- Artifacts
  This series contains several objects that belonged to Tilman including a small painted scroll, a silver medallion, a carved wooden box, and a leather portfolio.
  - Painted Scroll (Carton 38)
  - Carved wood (Carton 38)
- Computer Material
  This series contains a user’s guide for “The Research Assistant” computer program, several 5.5’’ floppy disks, a computer modem, and data processing magnetic tape.
  - User Guide for The Research Assistant computer program (Carton 37)
  - Modem (Carton 37)
  - Data Processing Magnetic Tape (Carton 37)